immigration.govt.nz 2019-05-24

# Privacy | Immigration New Zealand

This privacy statement applies to collection and security of personal and other information collected on this website and how it is used. You can also find out how you can access your personal information that we hold on you.

## Registered users

When you become a registered user of this website, personal information is collected from you. This information allows us to manage your account and is used to determine how the website is used.

## Collecting information

When you apply for a visa, INZ collects the information you provide to determine:

  * your identity
  * whether you are eligible to apply for a visa online.

The collection of your information is authorised by the Immigration Act 2009 (the Act) and the Immigration Regulations under the Act. The supply of your information is voluntary, but if you do not supply mandatory information required in any visa application you submit, your visa application may not be accepted.

Storage of information INZ has a legal obligation to protect any information we collect from you. INZ's online services are designed to meet national and international security standards to safeguard personal information collected.

You can find further information on INZ’s obligations to protect your information here:

The Privacy Commissioner's website has more information on the privacy laws in New Zealand.

You can contact the Privacy Commisioner at: Office of the Privacy Commissioner, PO Box 10094, Wellington 6143; or by email at enquiries@privacy.org.nz.

## Use of information

INZ will not disclose your information to any third-party in a form that will identify you except in the following circumstances:

  * Where you have consented to such disclosure.
  * Where such disclosure is required or permitted by the Privacy Act 1993, or otherwise required or permitted by law.

Please note that INZ is authorised to share information with other government agencies under applicable law.

INZ may also use your information to determine your entitlement to board a flight to New Zealand. Your personal information is not shared with airline check-in agents. When you check in to board a flight, the check-in agent only sees a boarding instruction based on the information you have provided in any application you submit.

[How we collect and use information about people flying in and out of NZ](https://www.immigration.govt.nz/about-us/policy-and-law/identity-information-management/how-we-collect-use-information-about-people-flying-in-out-nz)

INZ may use your information to contact you for research purposes or to advise you on immigration matters.

## Access to your personal information

You have the right to:

  * find out from us whether we hold personal information about you
  * access that information
  * request corrections to that information, if applicable.

In accordance with the 'Privacy Act 1993', we reserve the right to refuse your request if we have a good reason.

If you wish to check personal information held about you, contact your local Visa Application Centre (VAC) or INZ office. If you do not have a local VAC or INZ office, you can contact us or post your enquiry to:  Immigration New Zealand, PO Box 3705, Wellington 6140.

## Transparency statement

The Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment’s (MBIE) transparency statement describes the kind of information MBIE gathers to ensure it can effectively:

  * protect people, information, and places
  * ensure regulatory compliance, and
  * detect and prevents criminal offending.

_[MBIE’s transparency statement](https://www.mbie.govt.nz/about/open-government-and-official-information/transparency-statement/)_  | Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment

## Statistical information

You can browse this website without having to disclose any personal data. However, we may collect statistical information about your visit to help us analyse usage and improve the website. This information includes, but is not limited to:

  * users' IP addresses and location
  * users' search terms
  * pages accessed on the website
  * links that are clicked on
  * date and time of visits
  * previous visits to the website
  * users' operating systems
  * browsers and devices used when accessing the website.

This information is viewable by website administrators and certain other INZ staff. It may also be shared with other government agencies.

This information may be used for statistical or research purposes and will not be published in a form that could reasonably be expected to identify you.

## Cookies

This site uses Google Analytics cookies to provide traffic analysis which helps us improve our website.

It also uses third-party vendor remarketing tracking cookies (eg from Facebook and Google). These allow third-party vendors to show INZ ads on websites across the Internet based on someone's past visits to this website. This helps us to communicate to people who have shown an interest in living, working, studying or visiting New Zealand. On occasion, we may share this data with other New Zealand Government agencies (eg Education New Zealand and Tourism New Zealand) so that they can serve ads to these people too.

None of the cookies we use collect identifiable information about you.

You can disable or delete cookies through your browser settings. To learn more about cookies and how you can manage them in your web browser, visit the allaboutcookies.org website.

## Security

Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (MBIE) websites have security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. In order to maintain the cyber security of MBIE systems and information, MBIE systems are subject to ongoing monitoring (including activity logging), analysis and auditing. We may use information about your use of our websites and other IT systems to prevent unauthorised access or attacks on these systems or to resolve such events.

We may use this information even if you are not involved in such activity. MBIE may utilise services from one or more 3rd party suppliers to monitor or maintain the cyber security of its systems and information. These 3rd party suppliers will have access to monitoring and logging information as well as information processed on MBIE websites and other IT systems.
